

# MAXIME GÉLINAS SENIOR DEVELOPER

Saint-Hubert, QC • (514) 970-2803 • mgelinas@softframe.net

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

**EFFICIENT** Passionate expert who will quickly understand your code and who will effectively improve the

development of your applications to accelerate the growth of your business.

**CURIOUS** Self-taught by nature, I don't need an excuse to make me want to learn and move forward. It is

vital for me.

**INNOVATIVE** Always on the lookout for the best way to do it, I never settle for what is the old, comfortable

way.

#### RECENT EXPERIENCES

Jul 2021 - Jan 2022 DDD • CQRS •

.NET/C# • Angular • Nx • Storybook

**DESJARDINS** -LEAD DEVELOPER

Support and training of the developers of the team. Architecture of an Angular monorepo app. Implementation of the concepts of DDD and CQRS. Communication with internal Desiardins services.

Jan **2021 -** Jun **2021** 

.NET/C# • Angular • Entity Framework • OpenID Connect •

SQL Server

**DESJARDINS** – SENIOR DEVELOPER

Redesign of Desjardins' security screening system. Support for several thousand users. Development of the authentication process co-forming with the OpenID Connect standard. Communication with many external security screening services.

May **2019 -** Jan **2021** 

.NET/C# • Angular • Event Sourcing • CQRS • DDD • Azure • Firebase • Redux •

Cypress

ORDRE DES DENTISTES DU OC - FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Active participation in the architecture and redesign of the entire system of the Order where we have faced the many complexities related to a CQRS/ES system. Analysis and research on how to perform actions in the past and future using Event Sourcing. Contribution to the projection reconstruction system. Implementation of a real-time application with Angular, Firebase and NGXS. Configuring E2E tests with Cypress.

MAXIME GÉLINAS SENIOR DEVELOPER

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

<b>C#/.NET</b> 6 years		<b>ANGULAR • NGRX</b> 6 years		<b>GRAPHQL</b> 3 years	
<b>CYPRESS</b> 1 year		NODE.JS 3 years		<b>SQL SERVER</b> 3 years	
COSMOSDB 1 year		MONGODB 1 year		HTML/CSS 7 years	
METHODOLOGIES					
<b>DDD</b> 3 years		CQRS 2 years		<b>EVENT SOURCING</b> 1 year	
<b>SCRUM</b> 5 years		MICROSERVICES 3 years		<b>SOLID • DRY • YAGNI</b> 5 years	
TOOLS					
<b>AZURE</b> 1 year		<b>AZURE DEVOPS</b> 2 years		VISUAL STUDIO 6 years	

#### **DESIGN PATTERNS**

Optional object • Map-reduce • State • Strategy • Decorator • Factory • Builder • Chain of responsibility • Observer • Template method • Repository • Unit of Work • Null object • Special case

#### **OTHERS**

REST • Typescript • Sass • NestJs • Docker • Webpack • Firebase • PostgreSQL • Nx • Git • F# • AngularJS • Java • C++ • PowerShell • Android • Xamarin • PHP • MySQL • Bootstrap • JQuery

**MAXIME GÉLINAS** SENIOR DEVELOPER

#### **JOB EXPERIENCES**

Oct **2018 - May 2019** 

**ALLEMA** – FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

.NET/C# · ASP.NET MVC • Entity Framework

Contribution on some part-time .NET/C# projects in parallel with the University. To ask for an efficient return despite a contribution of 10 hours / week and a great autonomy due to work and remotely evenings and weekends.

Feb **2018** - Aug **2018** 

**SHERWEB** – FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

.NET/C# • Angular • Microservices • MongoDB · Scrum · OpenID · PowerShell Designed a microservices application capable of monitoring security vulnerabilities in multiple Office 365 accounts using PowerShell and APIs provided by Microsoft. Participating in the analysis of a multi-federation authentication service using OpenID Connect. Participation in architecture meetings and all Scrum meetings.

Nov **2017 -** Feb **2018** .NET/C# · REST · **Entity Framework** • Xamarin

**GROUPE CTT** - FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Realization of a RESTful web service developed and deployed 100% by me to manage the backend side of a mobile application. Implementation of high security of client-server communications.

Oct **2016 -** Oct **2017** PHP · MySQL · Bootstrap · JQuery

E-3 SOLUTIONS - BACKEND DEVELOPER

Modification and adaptation of an ERP according to the requests of a client. Creation, maintenance and online publication of several informative sites. Remote work. Contribution to the website of the newspaper Le Devoir.

May **2016 -** Mar **2017** .NET/C# • Angular • Scrum • DDD • REST **AXPER** – FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Development of a web application linked to a camera data acquisition system. Use of scrum methodology. Participation in Sprint Planning, Daily Scrums and Retrospective meetings.

Mar 2015 - Mar 2017 AngularJS • PHP • MySQL · Bootstrap

**IDMOBILES** – OWNER

Starting my own part-time web development company. The job involves developing websites, interacting with customers, defining needs, evaluating priorities and time required for each task and deploying the sites online.

#### ONLINE TRAINING

Date and Time Fundamentals • Versioning in an Event Sourced System by Greg Young • Exploring CQRS and Event Sourcing · CQRS in Practice · Building a RESTful API with ASP.NET Core · Writing Purely Functional Code in C# · Making Your C# Code More Functional • Microservices Architecture • Developing with .NET on Microsoft Azure -Getting Started • Making your C# Code More Object-Oriented • Tactical Design Patterns in .NET: Creating Objects • Tactical Design Patterns in .NET: Control flow • Tactical Design Patterns in .NET: Managing Responsibilities • Writing Highly Maintainable Unit Tests

MAXIME GÉLINAS SENIOR DEVELOPER

#### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

Sept **2019 -** Nov **2020** 

**LEARNUPFRONT** – PROJET PERSONNEL

Node.js • GraphQL •
Angular • NgRx •
Cypress • Docker •
Azure • PostgreSQL

Realization of a pre-hiring training platform. Analysis of the business area. Development of an Angular client, a GraphQL API and a PostgreSQL database. Implementation of CI and automatic deployments on Azure. E2E tests with Cypress. Interactions with potential customers. Launch of the promotional website.

Déc **2018** - Oct **2019**.NET/C# • DDD •
CQRS • Event

Sourcing • REST

**AIRVIEW** 

Realization of a fictitious project of booking airline tickets to synthesize and perfect my skills in DDD, CQRS, Event Sourcing and REST. This project aims to first facilitate my learning by using a concrete application case and to help me target the generalizable code and then move it to SolidStack.

Févr 2018 - Juill 2019
.NET/C# • DDD •
CQRS • Event
Sourcing • REST

**SOLIDSTACK** 

of a .NET framework to facilitate the implementation of a project focused on the following methodologies: DDD, CQRS, Event Sourcing and REST. The project is therefore made up of several NuGet packages in which we find several design patterns including the following: Option, Repository, Unit of Work, Value Object.

# **OTHER ACHIEVEMENTS**

Jul **2017 -** Sept **2017** 

JOURNAL LE DEVOIR - E-3 SOLUTIONS

PHP • MySQL • Web
Notifications •
Service Worker

Adaptation of the new client web platform of the popular newspaper Le Devoir with existing server features. Added client-side and server-side browser notifications with Service Worker and Google's API.

Nov 2016 - Feb 2017 AngularJS • PHP • HTML/CSS • MySQL **PHYSIO DES PATRIOTES** – IDMOBILES

Creation of a basic informative website with a CMS and an HTML/CSS theme built from scratch.

May 2016 - Aug 2016 AngularJS • PHP • HTML/CSS • MySQL **MICHEL ROBICHAUD** – IDMOBILES

Construction of a real estate website synchronized with Centris real estate data and implementation of a newsletter.

**MAXIME GÉLINAS** SENIOR DEVELOPER

### **EDUCATION**

BACCALAUREATE, COMPUTER SCIENCE (WITH INTERNSHIPS)

2 years

University of Sherbrooke, QC

**COLLEGIATE, COMPUTER SCIENCE** 

CEGEP of St-Hyacinthe, QC

4 years

# **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

Climbing • Kayaking • Hiking • Camping • Traveling • Martial Arts INTERESTS

French (primary) • English (advanced) LANGUAGES





